<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>xvnpw personal blog</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on xvnpw personal blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 10:14:47 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xvnpw.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 11:06:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://xvnpw.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hi. I&amp;rsquo;m security researcher, bug bounty hunter and appsec engineer.</description></item><item><title>From . in regex to SSRF - part 3</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/from-dot-in-regex-to-ssrf-part-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 10:14:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/from-dot-in-regex-to-ssrf-part-3/</guid><description>This is last part of my stories about exploiting service with SSRF bug. Part 1 is available here, and part 2 here.
This part is focused on abusing Node.js and node-fetch library. I will try to &amp;ldquo;talk&amp;rdquo; with Redis service using CRLF injection in http parser.
For convenience Redis service will be simulated by nc -vvlp 6379.
Test environment from my Kali 2020.1b:
Node.js version 10.19.0 node-fetch version 2.6.0 CRLF Injection Lets start with PayloadsAllTheThings.</description></item><item><title>From . in regex to SSRF - part 2</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/from-dot-in-regex-to-ssrf-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 10:14:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/from-dot-in-regex-to-ssrf-part-2/</guid><description>In this story I will continue my journey to exploit Server Side Request Forgery (SSRF). Part 1 is available here.
What is state of the game up to now? I have found service that is vulnerable to SSRF by executing the REST call and by passing domain name check:
https://api.example.org/image-converter/https://www-example.org
I have registered domain name: www-example.org and add for it CNAME record to my EC2 server.
But wait a second. This is not yet &amp;ldquo;SSRF&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>From . in regex to SSRF - part 1</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/from-dot-in-regex-to-ssrf-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 10:14:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/from-dot-in-regex-to-ssrf-part-1/</guid><description>In test of one application I have encountered bug in regex that leaded to Server Side Request Forgery (SSRF). Way of finding it was huge fun and excitement. It was also my first bug on production system ever.
During a recon I have found service called image-converter. It was definitely interesting, but not straight forward to exploit. I had no example of usage it and on simple GET request I was just getting:</description></item></channel></rss>