<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Langchain on xvnpw personal blog</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/tags/langchain/</link><description>Recent content in Langchain on xvnpw personal blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 14:59:02 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xvnpw.github.io/tags/langchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leveraging LLMs for Threat Modeling - Claude 3 Opus vs GPT-4</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/leveraging-llms-for-threat-modelling-claude-3-vs-gpt-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 14:59:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/leveraging-llms-for-threat-modelling-claude-3-vs-gpt-4/</guid><description>Claude 3 Opus is latest and most powerful model from Anthropic. Is it able to overcome GPT-4?
Revisiting the Experiment If you wish to understand more about the experiment structure, you can refer to my previous post. But here&amp;rsquo;s a quick recap:
I used markdown files describing a fictional project, AI Nutrition-Pro, with input:
PROJECT.md - high level project description ARCHITECTURE.md - architecture description 0001_STORE_DIET_INTRODUCTIONS.md - user story I tasked the AI models with four types of analysis: high-level security design review, threat modeling, security-related acceptance criteria and review of architecture:</description></item><item><title>Reviewing Your Architecture Using LLMs</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/review_your_architecture_using_llms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 08:59:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/review_your_architecture_using_llms/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed utilizing LLMs for threat modeling. Building on that, I&amp;rsquo;ve incorporated a new feature in my ai-threat-modeling-action on GitHub. It now allows you to review your project&amp;rsquo;s architectural description using LLMs. Let&amp;rsquo;s delve deeper 🤿!
Revisiting the Experiment For a detailed understanding of the experiment&amp;rsquo;s structure, you can revisit my previous post. However, here&amp;rsquo;s a brief summary:
I utilized markdown files, which described a fictional project named AI Nutrition-Pro, as input:</description></item><item><title>Leveraging LLMs for Threat Modeling - GPT-3.5 vs Claude 2 vs GPT-4</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/leveraging-llms-for-threat-modelling-gpt-3.5-vs-claude2-vs-gpt-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 08:59:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/leveraging-llms-for-threat-modelling-gpt-3.5-vs-claude2-vs-gpt-4/</guid><description>In a bid to uncover which AI model is best at threat modeling, I put GPT-3.5, Claude 2, and GPT-4 to the test. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how they performed.
Ethan Mollick, a professor at The Wharton School, once said something that perfectly captures my experience with these AI models. It feels as if they&amp;rsquo;re striving to answer questions in the simplest way possible 😏 However, you can get around this by asking for detailed explanations or step-by-step thinking.</description></item><item><title>Leveraging LLMs for Threat Modeling - GPT-3.5</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/leveraging-llms-for-threat-modelling-gpt-3.5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 18:59:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/leveraging-llms-for-threat-modelling-gpt-3.5/</guid><description>In this article, I delve into the AI Nutrition-Pro experiment, a research project exploring the potential of LLMs in enhancing security practices during the design phase of DevSecOps: threat modeling and security review.
DevSecOps: A Brief Overview DevSecOps merges the principles of development, security, and operations to create a culture of shared responsibility for software security. The three main goals of DevSecOps are:
Shift Left Security: Identifying and addressing security vulnerabilities as early as possible in the software development lifecycle.</description></item></channel></rss>