<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apisix on xvnpw personal blog</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/tags/apisix/</link><description>Recent content in Apisix on xvnpw personal blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 22:59:05 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xvnpw.github.io/tags/apisix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bug bounty tips for nginx $request_uri path traversal bypass</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/bug_bounty_tips_for_nginx_request_uri_path_traversal_bypass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 22:59:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/bug_bounty_tips_for_nginx_request_uri_path_traversal_bypass/</guid><description>In this article, I will extend topic by bug bounty tips for weaknesses in authentication/authorization implementation in relation to nginx&amp;rsquo;s $request_uri variable.
APIs This vulnerability is for APIs. Best scenario are microservice deployed to Kubernetes and exposed by ingress controller.
Using paths API that you are playing with, need to use paths to address services, e.g.:
OK! https://api.example.com/user-service https://api.example.com/customer-service ... NOT OK! https://user.example.com/ https://customer.example.com/ First set of URLs is good for exploitation, as you can try sending request with https://api.</description></item><item><title>CVE-2021-43557: Apache APISIX: Path traversal in request_uri variable</title><link>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/cve_2021_43557_apache_apisix_path_traversal_in_request_uri_variable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 20:59:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://xvnpw.github.io/posts/cve_2021_43557_apache_apisix_path_traversal_in_request_uri_variable/</guid><description>In this article I will present my research on insecure usage of $request_uri variable in Apache APISIX ingress controller. My work end up in submit of security vulnerability, which was positively confirmed and got CVE-2021-43557. At the end of article I will mention in short Skipper which I tested for same problem.
What is APISIX ? From official website:
Apache APISIX is a dynamic, real-time, high-performance API gateway. APISIX provides rich traffic management features such as load balancing, dynamic upstream, canary release, circuit breaking, authentication, observability, and more.</description></item></channel></rss>